<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>free range statistics</title>
		<description>I write about applications of data and analytical techniques like statistical modelling and simulation to real-world situations. I show how to access and use data, and provide examples of analytical products and the code that produced them.</description>		
		<link>https://freerangestats.info</link>
		<atom:link href="https://freerangestats.info/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Deaths per firearm violence event</title>
				        
				
					<description>A negative binomial model isn&#39;t adequate for modelling the number of people killed per firearm incident in the USA; the real data has more events of one death, and also more extreme values, than the model.  But estimating the model was an interesting exercise in fitting a single negative binomial model to two truncated subsets of data.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/04/01/truncated-negbin-gun-violence</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/04/01/truncated-negbin-gun-violence</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Truncated Poisson distributions in R and Stan</title>
				        
				
					<description>Two ways of fitting a model to truncated data.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/03/20/truncated-poisson</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/03/20/truncated-poisson</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Do tweeps with more followers follow tweeps with more followers?</title>
				        
				
					<description>I investigate a question about the Twitter network, and find that generally (until reaching a level of fame few of us aspire to), having more followers oneself is associated with following people who have less followers, not more.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/02/24/following-followers</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/02/24/following-followers</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Books I liked in 2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>I outline the stats- and data-related books I most enjoyed reading in 2017.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/02/17/books-2017</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/02/17/books-2017</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Visualising an ethnicity statistical classification</title>
				        
				
					<description>An interactive network graph is a great way to understand a statistical classification standard.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/02/10/ethnicity</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/02/10/ethnicity</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Average spend, activities and length of visit in the NZ International Visitor Survey</title>
				        
				
					<description>Resolving an apparent conundrum where the mean spend and other value variables seems to be higher for nearly everywhere... an adventure in double counting (individuals contributing to multiple groups&#39; averages).</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/02/03/ivs</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/02/03/ivs</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>How to recruit data analysts for the public sector</title>
				        
				
					<description>Reflections on recruiting data scientists for the public sector, which could maybe be used as practical guidance for someone.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/01/23/recruiting</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/01/23/recruiting</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Some quirks with R and SQL Server</title>
				        
				
					<description>I note for future use a couple of things to be aware of in using R to schedule the execution of SQL scripts.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2017/12/09/sql-and-r</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2017/12/09/sql-and-r</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Seasonality of plagues</title>
				        
				
					<description>Playing around with polishing graphics, including an animation, of the seasonality of plague deaths in medieval Europe, early modern Europe, and nineteenth century India and China.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2017/11/19/plague-seasonality</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2017/11/19/plague-seasonality</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New Zealand fatal traffic crashes</title>
				        
				
					<description>I explore half a million rows of disaggregated crash data for New Zealand, and along the way illustrate geo-spatial projections, maps, forecasting with ensembles of methods, a state space model for change over time, and a generalized linear model for understanding interactions in a three-way cross tab.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2017/10/15/traffic-crashes</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2017/10/15/traffic-crashes</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>