<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>free range statistics</title>
		<description>I write about applications of data and analytical techniques like statistical modelling and simulation to real-world situations. I show how to access and use data, and provide examples of analytical products and the code that produced them.</description>		
		<link>http://freerangestats.info</link>
		<atom:link href="http://freerangestats.info/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Principal components and penguins</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>Beware that the direction of a principal component can vary depending on the sequence of the original data.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2021/06/14/pc-penguins</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2021/06/14/pc-penguins</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Making a database of security prices and volumes</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I make a SQLite database of daily observations of Australian security prices, volumes and short positions.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2021/02/14/stock-database</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2021/02/14/stock-database</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Visualising stock prices and volume</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>After some experimenting with how to show stock price and volume at the same time, I conclude unsuprisingly that the charts commonly used in finance are pretty much fit for purpose, but alternative presentations have their place too.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2021/02/05/stock-visualizations</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2021/02/05/stock-visualizations</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Shiny in production for commercial clients</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>Shiny can be an effective platform to quickly build data-intensive web applications that otherwise would not be commercially viable. The rationale for using Shiny at the right time is convenience, cost, and statistical and graphics power.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/12/21/rmit-dashboard</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/12/21/rmit-dashboard</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Animated map of World War I UK ship positions</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>An animated map of UK Royal Navy ship locations during World War I.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/12/05/wwi-ships</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/12/05/wwi-ships</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Reproduce analysis of a political attitudes experiment</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I reproduce the analysis of data from a recently published experiment on the impact on Australians&#39; and New Zealanders&#39; attitudes to overseas aid of being exposed to writing about Chinese aid in the Pacific. Along the way I muse about the Table 2 fallacy, and try to avoid it while still using multiple imputation, bootstrap and adjusting for covariates to slightly improve the original analysis.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/11/14/aid-attitudes</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/11/14/aid-attitudes</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Hamlet, data models, interaction graphs and other cool stuff</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I play around with Hamlet&#39;s text to set it up for easy data analysis. Hamlet is awesome, this post is really just an excuse to spend time with it; but it does perhaps start to put together something useful about data models for text.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/10/11/hamlet</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/10/11/hamlet</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Facebook survey data for the Covid-19 Symptom Data Challenge</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>Two huge surveys of Facebook users seem to provide valuable new information on how the world is responding to Covid-19, but I am very unsure about whether they have potential to enable earlier detection of outbreaks.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/10/04/covid-symptom-challenge</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/10/04/covid-symptom-challenge</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Free text in surveys - important issues in the 2017 New Zealand Election Study</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I try out biterm topic modelling on a free text question in the 2017 New Zealand Election Study about the most important issue in the election.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/09/26/nzes-issues</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/09/26/nzes-issues</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Trying out Processing</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I have a go at using the Processing programming language, which was developed to help graphic designers but has a broad bunch of potential applications. While Processing proper sits on top of Java, there&#39;s a handy implementation in JavaScript.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/09/13/processing-language</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/09/13/processing-language</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>