<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Peter&#39;s stats stuff</title>
		<description>I write about applications of data and analytical techniques like statistical modelling and simulation to real-world situations. I show how to access and use data, and provide examples of analytical products and the code that produced them.</description>		
		<link>http://ellisp.github.io</link>
		<atom:link href="http://ellisp.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Skill v luck in determining backgammon winners</title>
				        
				
					<description>I explore the relationship between decision quality and winning in backgammon, using data from XG-Gammon analysis of matches on FIBS and grid.gammon</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/03/19/elo-pr-luck</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/03/19/elo-pr-luck</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Explore  with Shiny the impact of sample size on &quot;p-charts&quot;</title>
				        
				
					<description>I built a Shiny app to help people see what happens to a statistical quality control p-chart when the sample size, period of time, target defect rate and true defect rate get played around with.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/03/06/control-charts</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/03/06/control-charts</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New Zealand Tourism Dashboard pushes Shiny to the max</title>
				        
				
					<description>The New Zealand Ministry of Business, Innovation and Employment has released a &quot;Tourism Dashboard&quot; built with R and Shiny to give flexible access to the full range of official statistics on tourism in New Zealand (disclaimer - I work for them).</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/02/24/tourism-dashboard</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/02/24/tourism-dashboard</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Dynamic Stochastic General Equilibrium models made (relatively) easy with R</title>
				        
				
					<description>The gEcon R package makes it (relatively) easy to define and calibrate Computable General Equilibrium models and their more nuanced next-generation successors, Dynamic Stochastic General Equilibrium models.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/02/20/DSGE</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/02/20/DSGE</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>ggseas package for seasonal adjustment on the fly with ggplot2</title>
				        
				
					<description>Introducing an R package to do seasonal adjustment on the fly with ggplot2</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/02/08/ggseas</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/02/08/ggseas</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Data from the World Health Organization API</title>
				        
				
					<description>Eric Persson&#39;s new WHO package makes it easy for R users to access data from the World Health Organization</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/02/06/world-health-organization</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/02/06/world-health-organization</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Better prediction intervals for time series forecasts</title>
				        
				
					<description>Hybrid forecasts - averages of single-model forecasts - are commonly used to produce point estimates that are better than any of the contributing forecast models.  I show how prediction intervals can be constructed for a hybrid forecast that have more accurate coverage than most commonly used prediction intervals (ie 80% of actual observations do indeed turn out to be within the 80% confidence interval), tested on the 3,003 M3 forecasting competition datasets.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/01/30/hybrid-forecasts</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/01/30/hybrid-forecasts</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Filling in the gaps - highly granular estimates of income and population for New Zealand from survey data</title>
				        
				
					<description>I use Random Forests to create estimated income distributions for small (sometimes non-existent) subsets of the New Zealand population, using the 2011 New Zealand Income Survey.  The estimated distributions are showcased in an interactive web app.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/01/23/nzis-estimates</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/01/23/nzis-estimates</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A (not too talkative) twitterbot is born</title>
				        
				
					<description>I&#39;ve set up a twitter bot who (infrequently) retweets popular tweets about rstats with praise, repeats assorted R wisdom, and babbles about R.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/12/29/Rrobot-born</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/12/29/Rrobot-born</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Network charts of commuting in New Zealand with R and D3</title>
				        
				
					<description>Commuting patterns between districts and cities in New Zealand are used to illustrate static (for printing) and interactive (for the web) network charts with R and D3.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/12/26/commuting-network</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/12/26/commuting-network</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>