<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Peter&#39;s stats stuff</title>
		<description>I write about applications of data and analytical techniques like statistical modelling and simulation to real-world situations. I show how to access and use data, and provide examples of analytical products and the code that produced them.</description>		
		<link>http://ellisp.github.io</link>
		<atom:link href="http://ellisp.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Dual axes time series plots may be ok sometimes after all</title>
				        
				
					<description>Dual axis time series charts are often deprecated, but the standard alternatives have weaknesses too.  In some circumstances, if done carefully, dual axis time series charts may be ok after all.  In particular, you can choose two vertical scales so the drawing on the page is equivalent to drawing two indexed series, but retaining the meaningful mapping to the scale of the original variables.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/08/18/dualaxes</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/08/18/dualaxes</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Elastic net regularization of a model of burned calories</title>
				        
				
					<description>Elastic net regularization of estimates is a good way of dealing with collinearity and feature selection; this is illustrated with a simple dataset of 30 daily observations from a fitbit tracker.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/08/13/fitbit-lasso</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/08/13/fitbit-lasso</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>nzcensus on GitHub</title>
				        
				
					<description>Demonstration analysis of area unit demographic data from the nzcensus R package on GitHub, which is approaching more maturity and readiness for general use.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/08/04/nzcensus-gam-elastic-lm</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/08/04/nzcensus-gam-elastic-lm</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>nzelect 0.2.0 on CRAN</title>
				        
				
					<description>The nzelect R package is now available on CRAN; so far it has aggregate results by voting place for the New Zealand 2014 general election.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/07/14/nzelect-cran</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/07/14/nzelect-cran</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Animated world inequality map</title>
				        
				
					<description>Animated over time choropleth map of intra-country inequality, where data exist, using University of Texas Inequality Project data.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/07/02/ehii-map</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/07/02/ehii-map</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>International Household Income Inequality data</title>
				        
				
					<description>I explore the University of Texas Inequality Project&#39;s Estimated Household Income Inequality data, which provides modelled estimates of inequality for more than 150 countries from 1963 to 2008.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/06/30/ehii</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/06/30/ehii</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Monthly Regional Tourism Estimates</title>
				        
				
					<description>My day-job released new data on estimated tourism spend by region in New Zealand, by month.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/06/16/mrtes</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/06/16/mrtes</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Presentation slides on using graphics</title>
				        
				
					<description>Excellent statistical graphics usually reveal multivariate interactions and comparisons, and combine high data density with a minimum of ink that doesn&#39;t directly represent data.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/06/14/graphics-presentation</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/06/14/graphics-presentation</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Bootstrap and cross-validation for evaluating modelling strategies</title>
				        
				
					<description>I compare &#39;simple&#39; bootstrap, &#39;enhanced&#39; (optimism-correcting) bootstrap, and repeated k-fold cross-validation as methods for estimating fit of three example modelling strategies.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/06/05/bootstrap-cv-strategies</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/06/05/bootstrap-cv-strategies</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Actual coverage of confidence intervals for standard deviation</title>
				        
				
					<description>The success rate (proportion of times the true value is covered by the interval) of 95% confidence intervals from the bootstrap when estimating population standard deviation can be very poor for complex mixed distributions, such as real world weekly income from a modest sample size (&lt;20,000).</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/05/29/standard-deviation-confidence-intervals</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/05/29/standard-deviation-confidence-intervals</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>