<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>free range statistics</title>
		<description>I write about applications of data and analytical techniques like statistical modelling and simulation to real-world situations. I show how to access and use data, and provide examples of analytical products and the code that produced them.</description>		
		<link>http://freerangestats.info</link>
		<atom:link href="http://freerangestats.info/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Ordering bars within their clumps in a bar chart</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>It turns out to be quite easy in R to reorder your bars within each clump, to produce a bad bar chart like the unfortunate example from Georgia doing the rounds.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/05/23/ordering-in-bar-charts</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/05/23/ordering-in-bar-charts</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Incidence of COVID-19 in Texas after adjusting for test positivity</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>Even when you adjust for test-positivity rates, the number of new COVID-19 cases per day in Texas is going up, although not as rapidly as the unadjusted numbers imply.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/05/17/covid-texas-incidence</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/05/17/covid-texas-incidence</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Test positivity rates and actual incidence and growth of diseases</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I look at several different ways of accounting for the information given us by high positive testing rates for COVID-19 and look at the impact on estimates of effective reproduction number at a point in time.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/05/09/covid-population-incidence</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/05/09/covid-population-incidence</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Pragmatic prediction intervals from a quasi-likelihood GLM</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>A pragmatic way of generating prediction intervals from a generalized linear model with a quasi-likelihood response, if you&#39;re prepared to make an additional assumption about the distribution of the response.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/04/18/pred-interval-from-log-linear</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/04/18/pred-interval-from-log-linear</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>How to make that crazy Fox News y axis chart with ggplot2 and scales</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I demonstrate the power of the transformation functionality in the scales R package by re-creating an eccentric Fox News chart.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/04/06/crazy-fox-y-axis</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/04/06/crazy-fox-y-axis</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Impact of a country&#39;s age breakdown on COVID-19 case fatality rate</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I have a go at quantifying how important different demographic profiles will be for country average case fatality rates for COVID-19.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/03/21/covid19-cfr-demographics</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/03/21/covid19-cfr-demographics</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>COVID-19 cumulative observed case fatality rate over time</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I have a quick look at how the observed case fatality rate of COVID-19 has evolved over time so far.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/03/17/covid19-cfr</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/03/17/covid19-cfr</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New Zealand Election Study webtool</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I release an improved and updated version of my crosstab webtool for exploring the New Zealand Election Study data, now covering 2017 as well as 2014, and letting the user explore relationship between party vote and a range of attitudes, experiences and demographics.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/03/07/nzes-app</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/03/07/nzes-app</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Log transform or log link? And confounding variables.</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I check the robustness of last week&#39;s analysis of height -&gt; weight by trying a different method of specifying and fitting the model, and checking to see if socioeconomic status is acting as a confounder (because better-off people are both taller and healthier).</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/03/01/bmi-2</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/03/01/bmi-2</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Body Mass Index</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I test the traditional BMI calculation against the actual distribution of height and weight in USA adults in 2018. I decide BMI is quite a good metric. I find that one prominent critique of the BMI gets the direction wrong for whom has their weight exaggerated by BMI.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/02/23/bmi</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/02/23/bmi</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>