<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Peter&#39;s stats stuff</title>
		<description>I write about applications of data and analytical techniques like statistical modelling and simulation to real-world situations. I show how to access and use data, and provide examples of analytical products and the code that produced them.</description>		
		<link>http://ellisp.github.io</link>
		<atom:link href="http://ellisp.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Books I like</title>
				        
				
					<description>My ten recommended books for applied statistics and data science.  Then 13 more!</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/01/14/books</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/01/14/books</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Cross-validation of topic modelling</title>
				        
				
					<description>Cross-validation of the &quot;perplexity&quot; from a topic model, to help determine a good number of topics.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/01/05/topic-model-cv</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/01/05/topic-model-cv</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Sparse matrices, k-means clustering, topic modelling with posts on the 2004 US Presidential election</title>
				        
				
					<description>I explore different sparse matrix formats in R and moving data from R to H2O.  Along the way I use k-means clustering and topic modelling to explore textual data from the Daily Kos blog on the 2004 US Presidential election.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/12/31/sparse-bags</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/12/31/sparse-bags</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Extracting data on shadow economy from PDF tables</title>
				        
				
					<description>The shadow economy as a percentage of GDP in wealthier countries is in decline; and had a spike in 2009 with the economic crisis.  More research is needed to adequately understand it.  Along the way I experiment with extracting data frames from PDF tables; and show it&#39;s always worthwhile looking at the same data in different ways, which can be as simple as freeing up the vertical axes of graphics.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/12/26/shadow-economy</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/12/26/shadow-economy</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>forecastHybrid 0.3.0 on CRAN</title>
				        
				
					<description>forecastHybrid 0.3.0 for ensemble time series forecasting is now on CRAN. Two new features are prediction intervals for the nnetar (neural network) component of the combination; and theta method models.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/12/24/forecastHybrid-0.3</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/12/24/forecastHybrid-0.3</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Air quality in Indian cities</title>
				        
				
					<description>Air pollution in Indian cities is unambiguously seasonal, and also might have a Diwali impact.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/12/18/air-quality-india</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/12/18/air-quality-india</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Extrapolation is tough for trees!</title>
				        
				
					<description>Tree-based predictive analytics methods like random forests and extreme gradient boosting may perform poorly with data that is out of the range of the original training data.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/12/10/extrapolation</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/12/10/extrapolation</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Why time series forecasts prediction intervals aren&#39;t as good as we&#39;d hope</title>
				        
				
					<description>A quick demonstration of the impact of inevitably random estimates of the parameters and meta-parameters in ARIMA time series modelling</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/12/07/arima-prediction-intervals</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/12/07/arima-prediction-intervals</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Error, trend, seasonality -  ets and its forecast model friends</title>
				        
				
					<description>I check out exponential smoothing state space models for univariate time series as a general family of forecasting models, and in particular the `ets`, `stlm` and `thetaf` functions from Hyndman&#39;s forecast R package.  For monthly and quarterly seasonal data, `thetaf` seems to be slightly outperformed by its more flexible and general cousins.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/11/27/ets-friends</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/11/27/ets-friends</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Declining sea ice in the Arctic</title>
				        
				
					<description>Adding a (small amount of) polish to a well known chart of seasonal Arctic sea declining over the years.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/11/24/seaice</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/11/24/seaice</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>