<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>free range statistics</title>
		<description>I write about applications of data and analytical techniques like statistical modelling and simulation to real-world situations. I show how to access and use data, and provide examples of analytical products and the code that produced them.</description>		
		<link>https://freerangestats.info</link>
		<atom:link href="https://freerangestats.info/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Stepwise selection of variables in regression is Evil.</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>Stepwise variable selection is bad and dangerous, and you shouldn&apos;t do it. It increases false positives. It drops variables that should be in the model. It gives biased estimates for regression coefficients. The problems are worse for smaller samples; higher correlation between the X variables; and models with weaker explanatory power for the y (i.e. lower R-squared).</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/09/14/stepwise</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/09/14/stepwise</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Gender and sexuality in Australian surveys and census</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I familiarise myself with the Australian Bureau of Statistics&apos; statistical Standard on sex and gender, and play around with some data from the Australian General Social Survey that has outputs reported by persons&apos; sexual orientation.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/09/08/sex-gender</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/09/08/sex-gender</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Sampling without replacement with unequal probabilities</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I play around with sampling from finite populations with unequal probabilities, where the R sample() function turns out not to work the way I had expected it to.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/08/31/ppswor</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/08/31/ppswor</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Ratios of indexed line charts</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I draw some quick charts of Australian economic indicators and ponder the implications. A ratio of two indexes can be a useful part of exploratory analysis.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/08/30/australian-economy</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/08/30/australian-economy</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Polar-centred maps</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I draw maps of the largest settlements closest to the north pole and to the south pole, based on an idea by &apos;Brilliant Maps&apos;.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/08/24/polar-maps</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/08/24/polar-maps</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Perturbing a non-symmetrical probability distribution</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>Inspired by a Toot from Thomas Lumley, I explore a situation where adding random noise to a distribution changes the median but not the mean.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/08/20/symmetry</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/08/20/symmetry</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Snakes and ladders</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>When playing Snakes and Ladders with the common rules actually used, it is more complex than a simple mathematical model; I simulate games and put forward some findings that could be useful in a future high stakes Snakes and Ladders game.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/08/10/snakes-and-ladders</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/08/10/snakes-and-ladders</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Population age changes in the Pacific</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I polish up some visualisations of demographic trends in the Pacific.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/07/27/aging-pacific</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/07/27/aging-pacific</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Reproducing and adapting the UN Population Projections</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I have a mostly successful go at cohort component population projections to replicate the UN&apos;s totals from their published parts, with an idea to making small changes to observations or assumptions that can build on the official projections.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/05/05/pop-projections</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/05/05/pop-projections</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The &apos;V20&apos; group of vulnerable countries and the MVI</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I compare the GDP per capita and scores on the UN Multidimensional Vulnerability Index (MVI) of the 68 economies in the &apos;V20&apos; group with other countries that aren&apos;t part of the V20.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2023/10/17/mvi-and-v20</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2023/10/17/mvi-and-v20</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>