<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>free range statistics</title>
		<description>I write about applications of data and analytical techniques like statistical modelling and simulation to real-world situations. I show how to access and use data, and provide examples of analytical products and the code that produced them.</description>		
		<link>http://freerangestats.info</link>
		<atom:link href="http://freerangestats.info/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Simulating simple dice games</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I play around with simulating some dice games.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/10/27/dice-games</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/10/27/dice-games</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Understanding the limitations of group-level inequality data</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>Cross-sectional country-level data will show a relationship between income inequality and life expectancy even if inequality itself has no direct impact on life exectancy; so long as there is changing marginal impact of individual income on individual life space (as of course there is).</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/10/07/inequality-groups</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/10/07/inequality-groups</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Sri Lanka visitor arrivals</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>Sri Lanka has a rapidly growing tourism industry, two international tourism seasons, and seasonality patterns in arrivals that vary according to country of origin.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/09/26/sri-lanka-arrivals</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/09/26/sri-lanka-arrivals</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Rents in Melbourne</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>Rents in Melbourne have on average grown fastest in suburbs that were the cheapest in 2000; at least for two and three bedroom flats and for two bedroom houses.  Also, scatterplots are awesome.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/08/31/melbourne-rents</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/08/31/melbourne-rents</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Estimating relative risk in a simulated complex survey</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>Simulating complex survey data in order to fit slightly mis-specified relative risk models, we find that confidence intervals&#39; coverage is pretty much as advertised if we use appropriate methods that adjust for the complex survey data, but under-perform if the data is treated naively as coming from a simple random sample.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/08/24/simulating-survey</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/08/24/simulating-survey</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Relative risk ratios and odds ratios</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>Explanation and demonstration with simulated data of the difference between relative risk ratios and odds ratios, and how to extract them from a generalized linear model.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/08/17/risk-ratios</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/08/17/risk-ratios</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Time series intervention analysis with fuel prices</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I look into whether the regional fuel tax in Auckland has led to changes in fuel prices in other regions of New Zealand.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/08/14/fuel-prices</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/08/14/fuel-prices</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Leading indicators of economic growth</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>A demo of a favourite combination of multiple imputation, bootstrap and elastic net regularization.  I look at what are good leading indicators, with reliable data available, of New Zealand&#39;s economic growth.  The results turn out to be last quarter&#39;s economic growth; food prices; visitor arrivals; car registrations; business confidence; and electronic card transactions.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/08/10/leading-indicators</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/08/10/leading-indicators</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Business confidence and economic growth</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I have a brief look at the relationship between reported business confidence in New Zealand and what actually happens down the track with economic growth.  Confidence can help (a bit) explain future growth; but current and past growth isn&#39;t helpful in explaining confidence.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/08/01/business-expectations</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/08/01/business-expectations</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Setting up RStudio Server, Shiny Server and PostgreSQL</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>A few months back, I set up a server on Amazon Web Services with a data sciencey toolkit on it. Amongst other things, this means I can collect data around the clock when necessary, as well as host my little RRobot twitter bot, without having a physical machine humming in my living room. There are lots of fiddly things to sort out to make such a setup actually fit for purpose.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/07/07/twitter-monitor</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/07/07/twitter-monitor</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>