<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Peter&#39;s stats stuff</title>
		<description>I write about applications of data and analytical techniques like statistical modelling and simulation to real-world situations. I show how to access and use data, and provide examples of analytical products and the code that produced them.</description>		
		<link>http://ellisp.github.io</link>
		<atom:link href="http://ellisp.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Election analysis contest entry part 4 - drivers of preference for Green over Labour party</title>
				        
				
					<description>Locations with more self employed, people with Bachelor degrees, no religion, and people living overseas five years ago were more likely to vote Green over Labour in the 2014 New Zealand General Election, and locations with more ethnically Asian and Pacific people, people born in New Zealand, and people with no qualification returned higher votes for Labour over the Greens.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/04/16/nzelect4</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/04/16/nzelect4</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Election analysis contest entry part 3 - interactive exploration of voting locations with leaflet and Shiny</title>
				        
				
					<description>I talk through some exploratory analysis of voting location with a Shiny application using the {nzelect} New Zealand General Election 2014 data.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/04/09/nzelect3</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/04/09/nzelect3</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Election analysis contest entry part 2 - building the nzelect R package</title>
				        
				
					<description>I explain the structure and techniques behind building the nzelect R package, which has New Zealand election results, in case anyone is interested or wants to adapt the process for other packages that rely on preparatory data munging.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/04/04/nzelect2</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/04/04/nzelect2</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Election analysis contest entry part 1 - introducing the nzelect R package</title>
				        
				
					<description>I introduce a new R package, with tidy versions of New Zealand election data (so far only for the 2014 general election).  We confirm and discuss some well-known results such as the tendency for the Labour Party to apparently under-perform on party vote; and identify patterns at the Territorial Authority and Regional Council level that are not usually available due to how voting behaviour is normally classified and reported on.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/04/03/nzelect1</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/04/03/nzelect1</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Seasonal decomposition in the ggplot2 universe with ggseas</title>
				        
				
					<description>I&#39;ve updated the {ggseas} R package on CRAN to version 0.4.0 and it now includes a ggplot2-based seasonal decomposition, rolling averages on the fly, and options to scale the data to an index.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/03/28/ggseas-update</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/03/28/ggseas-update</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Skill v luck in determining backgammon winners</title>
				        
				
					<description>I explore the relationship between decision quality and winning in backgammon, using data from XG-Gammon analysis of matches on FIBS and grid.gammon</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/03/19/elo-pr-luck</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/03/19/elo-pr-luck</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Explore  with Shiny the impact of sample size on &quot;p-charts&quot;</title>
				        
				
					<description>I built a Shiny app to help people see what happens to a statistical quality control p-chart when the sample size, period of time, target defect rate and true defect rate get played around with.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/03/06/control-charts</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/03/06/control-charts</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New Zealand Tourism Dashboard pushes Shiny to the max</title>
				        
				
					<description>The New Zealand Ministry of Business, Innovation and Employment has released a &quot;Tourism Dashboard&quot; built with R and Shiny to give flexible access to the full range of official statistics on tourism in New Zealand (disclaimer - I work for them).</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/02/24/tourism-dashboard</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/02/24/tourism-dashboard</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Dynamic Stochastic General Equilibrium models made (relatively) easy with R</title>
				        
				
					<description>The gEcon R package makes it (relatively) easy to define and calibrate Computable General Equilibrium models and their more nuanced next-generation successors, Dynamic Stochastic General Equilibrium models.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/02/20/DSGE</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/02/20/DSGE</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>ggseas package for seasonal adjustment on the fly with ggplot2</title>
				        
				
					<description>Introducing an R package to do seasonal adjustment on the fly with ggplot2</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/02/08/ggseas</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/02/08/ggseas</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>