<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Peter&#39;s stats stuff</title>
		<description>I write about applications of data and analytical techniques like statistical modelling and simulation to real-world situations. I show how to access and use data, and provide examples of analytical products and the code that produced them.</description>		
		<link>http://ellisp.github.io</link>
		<atom:link href="http://ellisp.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Presentation slides on using graphics</title>
				        
				
					<description>Excellent statistical graphics usually reveal multivariate interactions and comparisons, and combine high data density with a minimum of ink that doesn&#39;t directly represent data.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/06/14/graphics-presentation</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/06/14/graphics-presentation</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Bootstrap and cross-validation for evaluating modelling strategies</title>
				        
				
					<description>I compare &#39;simple&#39; bootstrap, &#39;enhanced&#39; (optimism-correcting) bootstrap, and repeated k-fold cross-validation as methods for estimating fit of three example modelling strategies.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/06/05/bootstrap-cv-strategies</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/06/05/bootstrap-cv-strategies</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Actual coverage of confidence intervals for standard deviation</title>
				        
				
					<description>The success rate (proportion of times the true value is covered by the interval) of 95% confidence intervals from the bootstrap when estimating population standard deviation can be very poor for complex mixed distributions, such as real world weekly income from a modest sample size (&lt;20,000).</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/05/29/standard-deviation-confidence-intervals</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/05/29/standard-deviation-confidence-intervals</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Visual contrast of two robust regression methods</title>
				        
				
					<description>I use animations to show some of the properties of least trimmed squares compared to a Huber M estimator as alternative robust regression estimation methods for a simple linear models.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/05/22/robust-regression</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/05/22/robust-regression</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Minimalist Tufte-inspired axis text with Scottish-New Zealand historical material</title>
				        
				
					<description>The breaks= argument in scales in the ggplot2 universe makes it simple to do minimalist Tufte-inspired scales where the text and tick marks show the actual data values rather than just regular intervals.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/05/14/scots-female-ratio</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/05/14/scots-female-ratio</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Announcing new forecastHybrid package</title>
				        
				
					<description>The new forecastHybrid package for R by David Shaub and myself provides convenient access to ensemble time series forecasting methods, in any combination of up to five of the modelling approaches from Hyndman&#39;s forecast package.  These are auto-selected autoregressive integrated moving average; exponential smoothing state space (both ets and tbats); feed forward neural network with a single hidden layer and lagged inputs; and forecasts of loess-based seasonal decomposition.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/05/07/forecastHybrid</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/05/07/forecastHybrid</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Election analysis contest entry part 4 - drivers of preference for Green over Labour party</title>
				        
				
					<description>Locations with more self employed, people with Bachelor degrees, no religion, and people living overseas five years ago were more likely to vote Green over Labour in the 2014 New Zealand General Election, and locations with more ethnically Asian and Pacific people, people born in New Zealand, and people with no qualification returned higher votes for Labour over the Greens.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/04/16/nzelect4</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/04/16/nzelect4</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Election analysis contest entry part 3 - interactive exploration of voting locations with leaflet and Shiny</title>
				        
				
					<description>I talk through some exploratory analysis of voting location with a Shiny application using the {nzelect} New Zealand General Election 2014 data.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/04/09/nzelect3</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/04/09/nzelect3</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Election analysis contest entry part 2 - building the nzelect R package</title>
				        
				
					<description>I explain the structure and techniques behind building the nzelect R package, which has New Zealand election results, in case anyone is interested or wants to adapt the process for other packages that rely on preparatory data munging.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/04/04/nzelect2</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/04/04/nzelect2</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Election analysis contest entry part 1 - introducing the nzelect R package</title>
				        
				
					<description>I introduce a new R package, with tidy versions of New Zealand election data (so far only for the 2014 general election).  We confirm and discuss some well-known results such as the tendency for the Labour Party to apparently under-perform on party vote; and identify patterns at the Territorial Authority and Regional Council level that are not usually available due to how voting behaviour is normally classified and reported on.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/04/03/nzelect1</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/04/03/nzelect1</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>