<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Peter&#39;s stats stuff</title>
		<description>I write about applications of data and analytical techniques like statistical modelling and simulation to real-world situations. I show how to access and use data, and provide examples of analytical products and the code that produced them.</description>		
		<link>http://ellisp.github.io</link>
		<atom:link href="http://ellisp.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Impact of omitted variables on estimating causal effects - simulations</title>
				        
				
					<description>It&#39;s much more important to get a well-specified model than worry about propensity score matching versus weighting, or either versus single stage regression, or increasing sample size.  A regression that includes all &quot;true&quot; 100 explanatory variables with only 500 observations performs better in estimating a treatment effect than any of those methods when only 90 of the 100 variables are observed, even with 100,000 observations.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/04/15/propensity-simulations</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/04/15/propensity-simulations</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Exploring propensity score matching and weighting</title>
				        
				
					<description>Compared to the older style propensity matching to create a pseudo control sample, it may be better to weight the full data by inverse propensity score because it doesn&#39;t discard data.  Performing a regression (rather than simple cross tabs) after the weighting or matching is a good idea to handle inevitable imperfections.  The whole family of methods doesn&#39;t necessarily deliver big gains over more straightforward single stage regressions.  And if you have omitted material variables you&#39;re in trouble whatever you do.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/04/09/propensity-v-regression</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/04/09/propensity-v-regression</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New Zealand election forecasts</title>
				        
				
					<description>My New Zealand Election Forecasts web page is up; and I have some reflections on election day randomness, and on quality control.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/03/26/election-forecasts</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/03/26/election-forecasts</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>House effects in New Zealand voting intention polls</title>
				        
				
					<description>I use generalized additive models to explore &quot;house effects&quot; (ie statistical bias) in polling firms&#39; estimates of vote in previous New Zealand elections.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/03/21/house-effects</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/03/21/house-effects</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Simulations to explore excessive lagged X variables in time series modelling</title>
				        
				
					<description>Adding lots of lagged explanatory variables to a time series model without enough data points is a trap, and stepwise-selection doesn&#39;t help.  The lasso or other regularization might be a promising alternative.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/03/12/stepwise-timeseries</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/03/12/stepwise-timeseries</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New data and functions in nzelect 0.3.0 R package</title>
				        
				
					<description>Version 0.3.0 of the nzelect R package now on CRAN includes historical polling data and a few convenience functions</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/03/11/nzelect-0.3.0</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/03/11/nzelect-0.3.0</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Visualising relationships between children&#39;s books</title>
				        
				
					<description>Statistical methods like hierarchical clustering and principal components analysis can help understand and visualise literary concepts but don&#39;t replace reading the books and engaging with them in traditional critical ways!</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/03/04/childrens-books</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/03/04/childrens-books</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Success rates of appeals to the Supreme Court by Circuit</title>
				        
				
					<description>It&#39;s important to use the correct denominator when considering performance.  While a high percentage (more than 50%) of decisions from the US appeal circuit courts that get all the way to the Supreme Court are overturned, this is only a tiny proportion of total appeals decided by the lower courts.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/02/26/appeal-circuits</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/02/26/appeal-circuits</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Moving largish data from R to H2O - spam detection with Enron emails</title>
				        
				
					<description>I finally solve my problem of writing large sparse matrices from R into SVMLight format for importing to H2O; and demonstrate application with spam detection trained on the Enron email data comparing a generalized linear model, random forest, gradient boosting machine, and deep neural network.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/02/18/svmlite</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/02/18/svmlite</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>US Presidential inauguration speeches</title>
				        
				
					<description>I do some basic textual analysis and visualization with US Presidential inauguration speeches.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/01/23/inaugural-speeches</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/01/23/inaugural-speeches</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>