<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Peter&#39;s stats stuff</title>
		<description>I write about applications of data and analytical techniques like statistical modelling and simulation to real-world situations. I show how to access and use data, and provide examples of analytical products and the code that produced them.</description>		
		<link>http://ellisp.github.io</link>
		<atom:link href="http://ellisp.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Average spend, activities and length of visit in the NZ International Visitor Survey</title>
				        
				
					<description>Resolving an apparent conundrum where the mean spend and other value variables seems to be higher for nearly everywhere... an adventure in double counting (individuals contributing to multiple groups&#39; averages).</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2018/02/03/ivs</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2018/02/03/ivs</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>How to recruit data analysts for the public sector</title>
				        
				
					<description>Reflections on recruiting data scientists for the public sector, which could maybe be used as practical guidance for someone.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2018/01/23/recruiting</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2018/01/23/recruiting</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Some quirks with R and SQL Server</title>
				        
				
					<description>I note for future use a couple of things to be aware of in using R to schedule the execution of SQL scripts.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/12/09/sql-and-r</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/12/09/sql-and-r</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Seasonality of plagues</title>
				        
				
					<description>Playing around with polishing graphics, including an animation, of the seasonality of plague deaths in medieval Europe, early modern Europe, and nineteenth century India and China.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/11/19/plague-seasonality</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/11/19/plague-seasonality</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New Zealand fatal traffic crashes</title>
				        
				
					<description>I explore half a million rows of disaggregated crash data for New Zealand, and along the way illustrate geo-spatial projections, maps, forecasting with ensembles of methods, a state space model for change over time, and a generalized linear model for understanding interactions in a three-way cross tab.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/10/15/traffic-crashes</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/10/15/traffic-crashes</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New Zealand 2017 election results</title>
				        
				
					<description>New Zealand&#39;s election results have been released and were within the range of my probabilistic predictions.  The pollsters did a good job.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/10/07/election-results</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/10/07/election-results</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>nzelect 0.4.0 on CRAN with results from 2002 to 2014 and polls up to September 2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>A new version of the nzelect R package is on CRAN, with election results by voting location back to 2002, and polls up to the latest election.  I show how to extract and understand the &quot;special&quot; votes and how they are different to advance voting.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/10/05/nzelect-0-4-0</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/10/05/nzelect-0-4-0</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Time-varying house effects in New Zealand political polls</title>
				        
				
					<description>I adjust my state-space model of New Zealand voting behaviour to allow for the house effect of one of the pollsters to change from the time they started including an on-line sample, and get some interesting results.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/09/16/time-varying-house-effects</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/09/16/time-varying-house-effects</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>R Markdown for documents with logos, watermarks, and corporate styles</title>
				        
				
					<description>I outline how I structure analytical project folder systems and some hints for matching R Markdown documents to a corporate style guide including adding logos, watermarks, and of course colours and fonts.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/09/09/rmarkdown</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/09/09/rmarkdown</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The long view on New Zealand political polls</title>
				        
				
					<description>New Zealand electoral polls going back 15 years</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/09/09/nzpolls-again</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/09/09/nzpolls-again</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>