<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Peter&#39;s stats stuff</title>
		<description>I write about applications of data and analytical techniques like statistical modelling and simulation to real-world situations. I show how to access and use data, and provide examples of analytical products and the code that produced them.</description>		
		<link>http://ellisp.github.io</link>
		<atom:link href="http://ellisp.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Stats NZ encouraging active sharing for microdata access projects</title>
				        
				
					<description>Excited that New Zealand&#39;s Government Statistician is promoting reproducibility and open access to code, tabular outputs and research products from research with confidentialised microdata.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/06/17/microdata-access</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/06/17/microdata-access</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Global choropleth maps of military expenditure</title>
				        
				
					<description>For choropleth maps showing the whole world, we don&#39;t need to stick to static maps with Mercator projections.  I like rotating globes, and interactive slippery maps with tooltips.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/06/04/military-gdp</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/06/04/military-gdp</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Sankey charts for swinging voters</title>
				        
				
					<description>Sankey charts based on individual level survey data are a good way of showing change from election to election.  I demonstrate this, via some complications with survey-reweighting and missing data, with the New Zealand Election Study for the 2014 and 2011 elections.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/05/21/nzes-sankey</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/05/21/nzes-sankey</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Web app for individual party vote from the 2014 New Zealand election study</title>
				        
				
					<description>Introducing a Shiny web tool for exploring individual characteristics and party vote in the 2014 New Zealand general election.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/05/14/nzes-app</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/05/14/nzes-app</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Modelling individual party vote from the 2014 New Zealand election study</title>
				        
				
					<description>I work through a fairly complete modelling case study utilising methods for complex surveys, multiple imputation, multilevel models, non-linear relationships and the bootstrap. People who voted for New Zealand First in the 2014 election were more likely to be older, born in New Zealand, identify as working class and male.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/05/06/nz-first</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/05/06/nz-first</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Luke-warm about micromaps</title>
				        
				
					<description>Linked micromaps are an ok way of presenting data and are probably the right tool in some circumstances; but they&#39;re not as cool as I thought they might be.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/04/30/micromaps</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/04/30/micromaps</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>More cartograms of New Zealand census data (district and city level)!</title>
				        
				
					<description>Shapefiles for cartogram by New Zealand Territorial Authority (ie District or City), with area proportional to population in 2013, have been added to the nzcensus package on GitHub.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/04/25/more-cartograms</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/04/25/more-cartograms</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Cartograms of New Zealand census data</title>
				        
				
					<description>Choropleth maps are useful ways of using fill colour to show densities, proportions and growth rates by political or economic boundaries, but can be visually problematic when large geographic areas represent few people, or small areas (ie cities) represent many.  One solution is a cartogram, and I have a go at using them to present New Zealand census data in this post and accompanying shiny app.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/04/23/cartograms</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/04/23/cartograms</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Impact of omitted variables on estimating causal effects - simulations</title>
				        
				
					<description>It&#39;s much more important to get a well-specified model than worry about propensity score matching versus weighting, or either versus single stage regression, or increasing sample size.  A regression that includes all &quot;true&quot; 100 explanatory variables with only 500 observations performs better in estimating a treatment effect than any of those methods when only 90 of the 100 variables are observed, even with 100,000 observations.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 15 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/04/15/propensity-simulations</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/04/15/propensity-simulations</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Exploring propensity score matching and weighting</title>
				        
				
					<description>Compared to the older style propensity matching to create a pseudo control sample, it may be better to weight the full data by inverse propensity score because it doesn&#39;t discard data.  Performing a regression (rather than simple cross tabs) after the weighting or matching is a good idea to handle inevitable imperfections.  The whole family of methods doesn&#39;t necessarily deliver big gains over more straightforward single stage regressions.  And if you have omitted material variables you&#39;re in trouble whatever you do.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/04/09/propensity-v-regression</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/04/09/propensity-v-regression</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>