<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Peter&#39;s stats stuff</title>
		<description>I write about applications of data and analytical techniques like statistical modelling and simulation to real-world situations. I show how to access and use data, and provide examples of analytical products and the code that produced them.</description>		
		<link>http://ellisp.github.io</link>
		<atom:link href="http://ellisp.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Getting started in applied statistics / datascience</title>
				        
				
					<description>If you want to be a data scientist or applied statistician, you need to study statistics, learn to write code, and learn *how* to learn (as lots of stuff seems to me to get out of date on a six month cycle).   This post doesn&#39;t have any short cuts, but as consolation I do show how to draw with R a variant of Drew Conway&#39;s famous Data Science Venn Diagram.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/08/30/starting-in-datascience</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/08/30/starting-in-datascience</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A better way of visualising income distributions with zeroes and negatives</title>
				        
				
					<description>I demonstrate a better way of visualising income distributions when they include zero and negative values rather than just putting them on a logarithmic scale and dropping the inconvenient values.  I use a modified power transformation, which applies a transformation like square root to the absolute value of the original variable and then restores the sign.  I apply the method to the New Zealand Income Survey 2011 data.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/08/21/visualising-distributions</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/08/21/visualising-distributions</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Importing the New Zealand Income Survey SURF</title>
				        
				
					<description>I tidy up the publicly available simulated unit record file (SURF) of the New Zealand Income Survey 2011, import into a database, and explore income distributions, visualising the lower distribution of weekly incomes New Zealanders of Maori and Pacific Islander ethnicity.  Along the way I create a function to identify modes in a multi-modal distribution.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/08/15/importing-nzis-surf</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/08/15/importing-nzis-surf</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Simulating backgammon players&#39; Elo ratings</title>
				        
				
					<description>I show how to convert from the Elo ratings of a backgammon player and their opponent and match length to the theoretical probability of winning.  I simulate a simple two player backgammon forum to show how Elo ratings vary at random around players &#39;true&#39; skill level.  Along the way, I demonstrate making animated graphics for a webpage.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/08/07/fibs-elo-ratings-basics</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/08/07/fibs-elo-ratings-basics</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New Zealand Data &amp; APIs on GitHub</title>
				        
				
					<description>I discuss a new listing of datasets in New Zealand, and demonstrate tidying up a publicly available dataset on number of welfare beneficiaries for use in an interactive web application.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/08/01/new-zealand-data-on-github</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/08/01/new-zealand-data-on-github</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Hello world!</title>
				        
				
					<description>Initial post with some musings on what this blog will be for.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/07/26/hello-world</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/07/26/hello-world</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>