<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>free range statistics</title>
		<description>I write about applications of data and analytical techniques like statistical modelling and simulation to real-world situations. I show how to access and use data, and provide examples of analytical products and the code that produced them.</description>		
		<link>http://freerangestats.info</link>
		<atom:link href="http://freerangestats.info/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Exploring swings in Australian federal elections</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I explore the data on two-party-preferred voting swings in Australian federal elections and tentatively introduce the ozfedelect R package.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2019/03/11/aust-election-2-swings</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2019/03/11/aust-election-2-swings</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Bayesian state space modelling of the Australian 2019 election</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I tidy up Australian polling data back to 2007 and produce a statistical model of two-party-preferred vote for the coming election.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2019/03/02/aust-election-1</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2019/03/02/aust-election-1</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Seasonality in NZ voting preference?</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I update the nzelect R package with the latest New Zealand polling data, and use a generalized additive model to look for a seasonal impact on support for the current government.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2019/02/20/voting-seasonality</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2019/02/20/voting-seasonality</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>What the world agrees with</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I load wave 6 of the World Values Survey into a database so it&#39;s possible to analyse more questions and countries at once, and find some interesting variations in what people agree with in different parts of the world.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2019/01/26/world-agreeing</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2019/01/26/world-agreeing</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Simulating Persian Monarchs gameplay</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>Persian Monarchs described by P. G. Wodehouse in one of his funniest novels is an extremely simple fictional card game, but the gambling makes it a game of skill, and we can even construct plausible different strategies for winning. A good strategy involving card-counting beats a non-counting alternative by about 4% and random wagering by 36%.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/12/23/persian-monarchs</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/12/23/persian-monarchs</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Number of births in the twentieth century</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>It turns out that about 10 billion people were born in total in the twentieth century.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/12/01/number-births</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/12/01/number-births</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Counting digits</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I have a play with counting how often particular digits turn up in numbers, starting with page numbers of a book based on a training exercise, and moving on to the so-called Benford&#39;s law or first-digit law.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/11/24/counting-digits</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/11/24/counting-digits</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A more systematic look at suppressed data</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>A more systematic comparison of different ways of dealing with cells in a cross tab that have been supressed for confidentiality. For the particular model tested here, the best thing to do is the simple method of replacing all suppressed cells with 5; this works even better than using the original unsuppressed data which is very unstable when many cell counts are near zero.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/11/18/suppressed-data-2</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/11/18/suppressed-data-2</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Suppressed data (left-censored counts)</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I experiment with some different ways of handling counts in tables that have been suppressed for confidentiality, and come up in favour of multiple imputation. The mice R package helpfully lets you define your own imputation algorithm.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/11/06/suppressed-data</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/11/06/suppressed-data</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Simulating simple dice games</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I play around with simulating some dice games.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/10/27/dice-games</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2018/10/27/dice-games</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>