<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>free range statistics</title>
		<description>I write about applications of data and analytical techniques like statistical modelling and simulation to real-world situations. I show how to access and use data, and provide examples of analytical products and the code that produced them.</description>		
		<link>http://freerangestats.info</link>
		<atom:link href="http://freerangestats.info/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Facebook survey data for the Covid-19 Symptom Data Challenge</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>Two huge surveys of Facebook users seem to provide valuable new information on how the world is responding to Covid-19, but I am very unsure about whether they have potential to enable earlier detection of outbreaks.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/10/04/covid-symptom-challenge</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/10/04/covid-symptom-challenge</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Free text in surveys - important issues in the 2017 New Zealand Election Study</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I try out biterm topic modelling on a free text question in the 2017 New Zealand Election Study about the most important issue in the election.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/09/26/nzes-issues</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/09/26/nzes-issues</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Trying out Processing</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I have a go at using the Processing programming language, which was developed to help graphic designers but has a broad bunch of potential applications. While Processing proper sits on top of Java, there&#39;s a handy implementation in JavaScript.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/09/13/processing-language</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/09/13/processing-language</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Mixture distributions and reporting times for Covid-19 deaths in Florida</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I look at some unusual data where the median was higher than the mode, and show how to model it in Stan as a mixture of two negative binomial distributions.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/09/06/mixture-distributions</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/09/06/mixture-distributions</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Time series cross validation of effective reproduction number nowcasts</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I confront past nowcasts of effective reproduction number for Covid-19 in Victoria with the best hindsight estimate, and confirm that the nowcasts lag change in the 7-14 days leading up to the time they are made.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/08/29/reff-cv</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/08/29/reff-cv</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Lines of best fit</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I have a go at synthesising data to re-create a controversial and much-criticised chart that used ordinary least squares to fit a line relating university subjects&#39; costs per student to the number of students in each subject.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/08/23/highered-ols</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/08/23/highered-ols</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Essentially random isn&#39;t the same as actually random</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>An observational study claiming to be an RCT might have something to say but there are far too many discretionary researcher choices taken to believe its findings. But I use this as a chance to play with statistical inference after estimating a regression via lasso.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/08/09/country-regression</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/08/09/country-regression</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Visualisation options to show growth in occupations in the Australian health industry</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>Exploration of change in occupations in the Australian health industry, and economy more broadly, from 1986 to the present.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/08/02/occupation-growth</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/08/02/occupation-growth</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Estimating Covid-19 reproduction number with delays and right-truncation</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>There is a fast growing body of knowledge and tools to help estimate effective reproduction number of an epidemic in real time; I have a go at applying the latest EpiNow2 R package to data for Covid-19 cases in Victoria, Australia.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/07/18/victoria-r-convolution</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/07/18/victoria-r-convolution</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Fixing scientific publishing and peer review</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>Science isn&#39;t broken, but journals are. A joint solution is emerging for disparate problems of access, quality control and replicability in scientific publishing.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
				<link>http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/06/13/publication-reform</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://freerangestats.info/blog/2020/06/13/publication-reform</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>