<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Peter&#39;s stats stuff</title>
		<description>I write about applications of data and analytical techniques like statistical modelling and simulation to real-world situations. I show how to access and use data, and provide examples of analytical products and the code that produced them.</description>		
		<link>http://ellisp.github.io</link>
		<atom:link href="http://ellisp.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Linear model with time series random component</title>
				        
				
					<description>Creating an animation to show why you can&#39;t ignore the time series element of data even when it&#39;s been created by a simple linear model</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/11/15/linear-model-timeseries</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/11/15/linear-model-timeseries</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Modelled Territorial Authority GDP for New Zealand</title>
				        
				
					<description>The Ministry of Business, Innovation and Employment (MBIE) published Modelled Territorial Authority Gross Domestic Product estimates for New Zealand 2000 to 2012 in October 2015, and plan to update annually from now on.  The data, method and an interactive web app are on the MBIE website and the source code is available on GitHub.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/10/30/MTAGDP</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/10/30/MTAGDP</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Silver flows in the seventeenth and eighteenth centuries</title>
				        
				
					<description>I rework into a simple animated GIF a classic set of two diagrams, originally by Jan DeVries in 2003, showing the flow of silver between continents in the seventeenth and eighteenth centuries.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/10/25/silver</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/10/25/silver</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Seasonal adjusment on the fly with X-13ARIMA-SEATS, seasonal and ggplot2</title>
				        
				
					<description>I show how to seasonally adjust published electronic card transactions spend in New Zealand using the US Census Bureau&#39;s excellent X-13ARIMA-SEATS software, the Spanish SEATS algorithm and Christoph Sax&#39;s seasonal R package; and how to build a new &quot;stat&quot; for ggplot2 to make it easy to do seasonal adjustment on the fly for a graphic of a time series split by various grouping dimensions.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/10/10/X13ARIMA-SEATS</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/10/10/X13ARIMA-SEATS</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Recruiting Analysts for dynamic cutting edge public sector team</title>
				        
				
					<description>In my day job I&#39;m running a recruitment process for two Principal Analysts, a Senior Analyst and an Analyst.  This is a great opportunity to get into one of the most interesting analytics teams in New Zealand. Applications close 14 October 2015.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/10/04/recruiting</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/10/04/recruiting</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Success rates of automated ARIMA fitting</title>
				        
				
					<description>Using an automated process to select the order of an ARMA time series model returns the true data generating process less than half the time even with simple data generating processes; and with more complex models the chance of success comes down nearly to zero even with long sample sizes.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/09/30/autoarima-success-rates</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/09/30/autoarima-success-rates</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>How to compare two blackbox timeseries generators?</title>
				        
				
					<description>A brute force method for comparing whether two data generating black boxes that produce time series are the same process or not. Basically, you need to use each black box to generate many instances, calculate the average result of the first black box at each point of time, and see if the instances generated by the second black box are noticeably more different from that average than are instances generated by the first.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/09/20/timeseries-differences</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/09/20/timeseries-differences</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Autocorrelation functions of materially different time series</title>
				        
				
					<description>Time series can have identical or similar autocorrelation functions but differ in important ways that may be material to your question of interest.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/09/19/timeseries-same-acf</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/09/19/timeseries-same-acf</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Sampling distribution of Gini coefficient</title>
				        
				
					<description>I explore the sampling distributions of estimates of Gini coefficients from a sample, using the New Zealand Income Survey 2011.  At the actual sample size of nearly 30,000, sampling error is negligible, and as low as a sample size of 1,000 a 95% confidence interval is (0.48, 0.55), precise enough for most purposes and certainly good enough given the non-sampling vagaries of the underlying data.  I discuss why individual and weekly income data - which is all I have to hand - returns a higher measure of inequality than does annual household income, the more usual and internationally-comparable (and completely valid) measure.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/09/12/inequality-stats-distributions</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/09/12/inequality-stats-distributions</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Transforming the breaks to match a scale</title>
				        
				
					<description>I follow up my ggplot2 version of John and Draper&#39;s modulus transformation from my last post. The default for creating new transformations using the {scales} package places the breaks for gridlines and labels in the scale at regular intervals on the original untransformed scale; I explore how to adjust for this.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/09/07/transforming-breaks-in-a-scale</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/09/07/transforming-breaks-in-a-scale</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>