<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Peter&#39;s stats stuff</title>
		<description>I write about applications of data and analytical techniques like statistical modelling and simulation to real-world situations. I show how to access and use data, and provide examples of analytical products and the code that produced them.</description>		
		<link>http://ellisp.github.io</link>
		<atom:link href="http://ellisp.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Update of `ggseas` for seasonal decomposition on the fly</title>
				        
				
					<description>ggseas 0.5.1 is available on CRAN.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/10/12/ggsdc-rents</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/10/12/ggsdc-rents</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New Zealand Election Study individual level data</title>
				        
				
					<description>Individual level data on voting behaviour are freely available from the New Zealand Election Study and everyone should have a go at analysing them!</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/09/18/nzes1</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/09/18/nzes1</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Why you need version control</title>
				        
				
					<description>Using version control software is a defining sign of a professional approach to serious data analysis</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/09/16/version-control</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/09/16/version-control</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Analysing the Modelled Territorial Authority GDP estimates for New Zealand</title>
				        
				
					<description>My presentation and paper on the development and use of &quot;Modelled Territorial Authority Gross Domestic Product&quot; for New Zealand, as presented to the New Zealand Association of Economists conference in June 2016</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/09/13/mtagdp</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/09/13/mtagdp</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Dual axes time series plots with various more awkward data</title>
				        
				
					<description>I finish enhancements of the dual axes time series plotting function in R so it handles reasonably well series that may start at different times, have different frequencies, or include negatives.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/08/28/dualaxes2</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/08/28/dualaxes2</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Dual axes time series plots may be ok sometimes after all</title>
				        
				
					<description>Dual axis time series charts are often deprecated, but the standard alternatives have weaknesses too.  In some circumstances, if done carefully, dual axis time series charts may be ok after all.  In particular, you can choose two vertical scales so the drawing on the page is equivalent to drawing two indexed series, but retaining the meaningful mapping to the scale of the original variables.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/08/18/dualaxes</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/08/18/dualaxes</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Elastic net regularization of a model of burned calories</title>
				        
				
					<description>Elastic net regularization of estimates is a good way of dealing with collinearity and feature selection; this is illustrated with a simple dataset of 30 daily observations from a fitbit tracker.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 13 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/08/13/fitbit-lasso</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/08/13/fitbit-lasso</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>nzcensus on GitHub</title>
				        
				
					<description>Demonstration analysis of area unit demographic data from the nzcensus R package on GitHub, which is approaching more maturity and readiness for general use.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/08/04/nzcensus-gam-elastic-lm</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/08/04/nzcensus-gam-elastic-lm</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>nzelect 0.2.0 on CRAN</title>
				        
				
					<description>The nzelect R package is now available on CRAN; so far it has aggregate results by voting place for the New Zealand 2014 general election.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/07/14/nzelect-cran</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/07/14/nzelect-cran</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Animated world inequality map</title>
				        
				
					<description>Animated over time choropleth map of intra-country inequality, where data exist, using University of Texas Inequality Project data.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/07/02/ehii-map</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/07/02/ehii-map</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>