<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Peter&#39;s stats stuff</title>
		<description>I write about applications of data and analytical techniques like statistical modelling and simulation to real-world situations. I show how to access and use data, and provide examples of analytical products and the code that produced them.</description>		
		<link>http://ellisp.github.io</link>
		<atom:link href="http://ellisp.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Filling in the gaps - highly granular estimates of income and population for New Zealand from survey data</title>
				        
				
					<description>I use Random Forests to create estimated income distributions for small (sometimes non-existent) subsets of the New Zealand population, using the 2011 New Zealand Income Survey.  The estimated distributions are showcased in an interactive web app.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/01/23/nzis-estimates</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2016/01/23/nzis-estimates</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A (not too talkative) twitterbot is born</title>
				        
				
					<description>I&#39;ve set up a twitter bot who (infrequently) retweets popular tweets about rstats with praise, repeats assorted R wisdom, and babbles about R.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/12/29/Rrobot-born</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/12/29/Rrobot-born</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Network charts of commuting in New Zealand with R and D3</title>
				        
				
					<description>Commuting patterns between districts and cities in New Zealand are used to illustrate static (for printing) and interactive (for the web) network charts with R and D3.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/12/26/commuting-network</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/12/26/commuting-network</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>X13-SEATS-ARIMA as an automated forecasting tool</title>
				        
				
					<description>X13-SEATS-ARIMA does not perform particularly well by itself as an automated forecasting tool on the 3,003 test data series in the M3 forecasting competition.  For 412 series it fails to fit a model without manual intervention.  When it does fit a model, on average they perform slightly worse than auto.arima from Hyndman&#39;s forecast package.  It works well as part of a hybrid approach, however.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/12/21/m3-and-x13</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/12/21/m3-and-x13</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Importance of exports and economic growth, cross-country time series</title>
				        
				
					<description>Fitting a mixed-effects model with auto-correlated residuals to longitudinal country-level data, showing how changing importance of exports is positively related to economic growth.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/12/12/exports-gdp</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/12/12/exports-gdp</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Inequality measures in the World Development Indicators</title>
				        
				
					<description>Introduces a new web-app to help navigate and explore the World Bank&#39;s World Development Indicators; and a one-off comparison of the inequality measures available in that collection (just 5 of the 3,500 series available).</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/12/05/wdi-inequality</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/12/05/wdi-inequality</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Deaths from assault over time in 40 relatively rich countries</title>
				        
				
					<description>Simple but effective graphics showing relative country standings with regard to deaths from assault, and trends over time.  Most countries in this group are seeing a decline in deaths from assault, from peaks in the 1970s, &#39;80s or &#39;90s.  Data are downloaded from OECD.Stat via their API and SDMX and this post shows how to do this, and also demos screen scraping with {rvest} - not that it needs any demo-ing, it&#39;s so user-friendly.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/11/26/violent-deaths</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/11/26/violent-deaths</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Create ARIMA time series from bottom up</title>
				        
				
					<description>Creating a range of ARIMA models by hand by manipulating white noise, instead of arima.sim(), to make clear exactly how they work, and a animation to see several of them unfold.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/11/21/arima-sims</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/11/21/arima-sims</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Linear model with time series random component</title>
				        
				
					<description>Creating an animation to show why you can&#39;t ignore the time series element of data even when it&#39;s been created by a simple linear model</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/11/15/linear-model-timeseries</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/11/15/linear-model-timeseries</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Modelled Territorial Authority GDP for New Zealand</title>
				        
				
					<description>The Ministry of Business, Innovation and Employment (MBIE) published Modelled Territorial Authority Gross Domestic Product estimates for New Zealand 2000 to 2012 in October 2015, and plan to update annually from now on.  The data, method and an interactive web app are on the MBIE website and the source code is available on GitHub.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/10/30/MTAGDP</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2015/10/30/MTAGDP</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>