<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>free range statistics</title>
		<description>I write about applications of data and analytical techniques like statistical modelling and simulation to real-world situations. I show how to access and use data, and provide examples of analytical products and the code that produced them.</description>		
		<link>https://freerangestats.info</link>
		<atom:link href="https://freerangestats.info/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>Depression incidence by county and vote for Trump</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>Multi-level modelling with spatial auto-correlation! I look at county level data on incidence of depression in 2020, and voting for Trump in the 2024 US Presidential election, and conclude that there&apos;s something there, but of course there are lots of potential explanations of what is behind the relationship.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/12/23/depression-and-vote</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/12/23/depression-and-vote</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Death rates by cause of death</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I explore death rates by cause of death with OECD data, for the USA and other countries. Causes of death that are relatively high in the USA include assaults, accidents, suicides; diseases of the nervous systems (including Alzheimer&apos;s); and diseases of the circulatory system (including heart attacks).</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/12/14/us-death-rates</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/12/14/us-death-rates</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Simulating Ponzi schemes</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I write a function to simulate Ponzi schemes with various types of &apos;investor&apos; growth, withdrawal rates, and extraction by the scammer / owner of the scheme.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/11/30/ponzi-schemes</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/11/30/ponzi-schemes</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Design effects for stratified sub-populations</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I look at the two different sorts of design effects that Stata will report for estimates from sub-populations of a complex survey, which vary depending on whether or not the hypothetical simple random sample we are comparing the complex survey to has the same sub-population sample sizes as the actual sample.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/11/16/design-effects</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/11/16/design-effects</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Regressions where the coefficients are a simplex.</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I compare some different ways of forcing the coefficients in a regression to form a simplex, all greater than zero and adding up to exactly one. Two methods - quadratic programming, and explicit modelling of the coefficients from a Dirichlet distribution - give essentially identical results that match the data generating process well.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/11/06/simplex-regression-coefficients</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/11/06/simplex-regression-coefficients</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Git, peer review, tests and toil</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I was honoured to give the third and final Ihaka Lecture in the 2024 series. My talk had the theme &quot;Making R work in government&quot;.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/09/28/ihaka-lecture</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/09/28/ihaka-lecture</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Prime numbers as sums of three squares.</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I explore the number of ways to make a prime number as the sum of squares of three positive integers.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/09/21/primes-squares</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/09/21/primes-squares</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Stepwise selection of variables in regression is Evil.</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>Stepwise variable selection is bad and dangerous, and you shouldn&apos;t do it. It increases false positives. It drops variables that should be in the model. It gives biased estimates for regression coefficients. The problems are worse for smaller samples; higher correlation between the X variables; and models with weaker explanatory power for the y (i.e. lower R-squared).</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/09/14/stepwise</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/09/14/stepwise</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Gender and sexuality in Australian surveys and census</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I familiarise myself with the Australian Bureau of Statistics&apos; statistical Standard on sex and gender, and play around with some data from the Australian General Social Survey that has outputs reported by persons&apos; sexual orientation.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/09/08/sex-gender</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/09/08/sex-gender</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Sampling without replacement with unequal probabilities</title>
				        
				
				
					<description>I play around with sampling from finite populations with unequal probabilities, where the R sample() function turns out not to work the way I had expected it to.</description>
				
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
				<link>https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/08/31/ppswor</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">https://freerangestats.info/blog/2024/08/31/ppswor</guid>
				
				  
				
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>