<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
	<channel>
		<title>Peter&#39;s stats stuff</title>
		<description>I write about applications of data and analytical techniques like statistical modelling and simulation to real-world situations. I show how to access and use data, and provide examples of analytical products and the code that produced them.</description>		
		<link>http://ellisp.github.io</link>
		<atom:link href="http://ellisp.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>New Zealand 2017 election results</title>
				        
				
					<description>New Zealand&#39;s election results have been released and were bang in the middle of my probabilistic predictions.  The pollsters did a good job.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/10/07/election-results</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/10/07/election-results</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>nzelect 0.4.0 on CRAN with results from 2002 to 2014 and polls up to September 2017</title>
				        
				
					<description>A new version of the nzelect R package is on CRAN, with election results by voting location back to 2002, and polls up to the latest election.  I show how to extract and understand the &quot;special&quot; votes and how they are different to advance voting.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/10/05/nzelect-0-4-0</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/10/05/nzelect-0-4-0</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Time-varying house effects in New Zealand political polls</title>
				        
				
					<description>I adjust my state-space model of New Zealand voting behaviour to allow for the house effect of one of the pollsters to change from the time they started including an on-line sample, and get some interesting results.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/09/16/time-varying-house-effects</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/09/16/time-varying-house-effects</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>R Markdown for documents with logos, watermarks, and corporate styles</title>
				        
				
					<description>I outline how I structure analytical project folder systems and some hints for matching R Markdown documents to a corporate style guide including adding logos, watermarks, and of course colours and fonts.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/09/09/rmarkdown</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/09/09/rmarkdown</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The long view on New Zealand political polls</title>
				        
				
					<description>New Zealand electoral polls going back 15 years</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/09/09/nzpolls-again</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/09/09/nzpolls-again</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>More things with the New Zealand Election Study</title>
				        
				
					<description>I introduce a new web app that allows nons-specialists to explore voting behaviour in the New Zealand Election Study, and reflect on what I&#39;ve done so far with that data.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/08/20/nzes-so-far</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/08/20/nzes-so-far</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Estimating Gini coefficient when we only have mean income by decile</title>
				        
				
					<description>Calculating the Gini coefficient for inequality directly of mean income by decile produces a slightly biased downwards estimate.  I correct for this and demonstrate on the World Panel Income Distribution data.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/08/19/quantiles-gini</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/08/19/quantiles-gini</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Sampling distribution of weighted Gini coefficient</title>
				        
				
					<description>I play around with the sampling distribution of Gini coefficients calculated with weighted data; and verify that the Gini calculation method in a recent Stats NZ working paper is the one in the acid R package.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/08/05/weighted-gini</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/08/05/weighted-gini</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Inter-country inequality and the World Development Indicators</title>
				        
				
					<description>I play around with population-weighted income inequality of countries with data from the World Development Indicators, re-creating (with some amendments) some graphics from Branko Milanovic&#39;s recent book &quot;Global Inequality&quot;.</description>
				
				<pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/07/22/inter-country-inequality</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/07/22/inter-country-inequality</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Who turned out to vote in the 2014 New Zealand general election?</title>
				        
				
					<description>I explore the demographic characteristics of who voted (and who didn&#39;t), out of people on the electoral roll, in the 2014 New Zealand general election.  I use multiple imputation and a generalized linear model with a quasibinomial response.  The people who vote tend to have characteristics associated with doing ok out of society (owning a home, having a partner, university qualifications, etc).</description>
				
				<pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +1200</pubDate>
				<link>http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/07/13/voter-turnout</link>
				<guid isPermaLink="true">http://ellisp.github.io/blog/2017/07/13/voter-turnout</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>